{
    "id": "8e7fcd3df780400c86a08c2b5b93d7e4",
    "title": "Simple Past Or Past Continuous Tense Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "0ce425c6cf87404093f3c0823097d3e7",
            "title": "Simple Past Or Past Continuous Tense",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I ............................. I didn't hear the door bell.",
                    "description": "We use the past continuous to talk about an action or situation that was going on at a particular point of time in the past. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "slept",
                        "was sleeping"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ......................... her many times but she didn't answer.",
                    "description": "We use the simple past to talk about finished actions in the past. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "phoned",
                        "was phoning"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "'What ........................... then?' 'I was watching TV.'",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "did you do",
                        "were you doing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He ......................... money from the rich and gave it to the poor.",
                    "description": "The simple past is used to talk about all types of finished actions in the past.",
                    "answers": [
                        "stole",
                        "was stealing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "'Did you meet James yesterday?' 'Yes, I .................... him.'",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "met",
                        "was meeting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The train ...................... at",
                    "description": "The simple past is used to talk about finished actions in the past. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "arrived",
                        "was arriving"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The children ............................. when their mother .................... home.",
                    "description": "When we talk about two past events, the past continuous is used to refer to the longer background action. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "slept, got",
                        "were sleeping, was getting",
                        "were sleeping, got"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I cooked dinner while Mike ............................ the house.",
                    "description": "The past simple can be used to talk about two actions that happened at the same time. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "was tidying",
                        "tidied"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ....................... dinner when the lights went out.",
                    "description": "The past continuous can be used to talk about a longer background action that was going on when another action took place. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "had",
                        "was having"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It ......................... me quite sometime to learn French.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "took",
                        "was taking"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "As I .............................. down the street, I saw a strange sight.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "walked",
                        "was walking"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ...................... a car last month.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "bought",
                        "was buying"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}